Denis Moroz

moroz.denis@gmail.com http://www.linkedin.com/in/dmoroz/ https://github.com/denismoroz

Summary

Principal software developer and senior software development team manager with over than 12 years of hi-tech industry experience. Passionate about learning, test driven development and quality improvement.

Languages and Technologies

Python, C++, Android, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, PyCharm, AndroidStudio, Git, Celery, D3D.js, Bamboo, Jira, Asana, Apache, Ngnix, Spark, MSVC++ 6.0, QT, Django, Flask, RabbitMQ, TDD, Scrum, Linux(Ubuntu), Android, Windows

Professional Experience

Software Developer, US based startup 2014.01-present, contract job, remote

Responsible for design of a mobile application backend and development of a database schema for MongoDB. Created REST API service to access backend functions. Used Flask to implement REST API. Archived reliable codebase support and minimized amount of bugs through use of unit tests for all backend API functions. Implemented use of Ngnix on server side for better system scalability. Created system administrator's interface using web UI with Flask and JavaScript to consume REST API services. Built a Spark script to fetch real-time information about system requests and added displayed requests statistics in administrator interface using D3D.js. Developed a set of acceptance tests to validate CI main chains of execution and verify quality of recent backend-side commits. That enabled company to ensure that backend of the system is stable after new code deployments and prevented broken releases. Managed development of the Android mobile client system that used developed backend REST API.

Senior Python Developer, Mobsafety 2013.03-2013.09, contract job, remote

Responsible for Mobile Device Management solution for iOS and Android devices. Managed a team of four developers working on backend part of the project that runs as WSGI handler using Flask and MongoDB. Used agile scrum methodology, two weeks iteration cycle and Jira to organize development workflow. Unit tests were used to ensure system stability. Bamboo server was used as continuous integration platform. Backend services were deployed in Amazon cloud using Juju deployment tool.

Python Developer, LatamIQ 2012.07 – 2013.02, contract job, remote

Company service was to grab and analyze economic indexes. My responsibility was to build set of services at backend on MySQL that will help to analyze, predict flows of economical indexes using several metrics.

Django Python Developer, Keeyword.com 2011.09 – 2012.06, contract job, remote

The company is building tools for keyword research. My task was to optimize PostgreSQL database schema to store at least 500k of keywords in one project and provide fast access to them.

Python/C++/C Developer, Visionica 2008.03 –2011.06, contract job, remote

Developed server side components for IP cameras recording system using MySQL database, backend run on Ubuntu. I took part in development of client side application for this system written in QT.

C/Python/C++/Game Mods Developer, PlayAll 2007.05 – 2008.03, contract job, remote

Developed several mods to control game flow for Q4, HL family, HL2 family, COD 1, COD2, UT2004,

Linux Kernel Module on C and user mode management application on Python to protect server side components.

C++ Developer, Check Point Belrus, 2005.01 – 2007.08

The project was connected with Linux Kernel module development and debugging in UML environment with crash dump analysis.

<u>C++ Intetics Company</u>, 2003.09 – 2004.12

Developed the system level security application for Win32 OS using MSVC 6.0. My tasks included driver management application plug-in, user interface and communication mechanism between LSP provider and driver.

Education

1998-2003, Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radio-Electronics.

MS of computer science, Major in Informational Security and Artificial Intelligence.

2015, Udacity Frontend Nano Degree – in progress.

Certification

June 2014, M101P MongoDB for Developers

Links

Online resume: http://denismoroz.github.io/fend-p2/

Casual game for Android written on C++: http://market.android.com/details?id=com.doandroid.clackboard